<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning on Dora&#39;s world</title>
    <link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Learning on Dora&#39;s world</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 18:50:05 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Good deep learning posts</title>
      <link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/good-deep-learning-blog-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 18:50:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/good-deep-learning-blog-posts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am an avid reader and spend a lot of time commuting between home and work. I use this time to read blogs, news and papers. In this article I present some cool blog posts that I found and a very short summary. I will add more links as time permits. I have divided blog posts based on the audience it caters to, beginners and intermediate. I believe experts would dive directly into reading papers and won&amp;rsquo;t spend much time reading blogs. Also, are some really good non-technical articles as deserts and some random posts relating to AI as side dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;starters&#34;&gt;Starters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-brief-overview-of-deep-learning-ilya-sutskever-http-yyue-blogspot-in-2015-01-a-brief-overview-of-deep-learning-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yyue.blogspot.in/2015/01/a-brief-overview-of-deep-learning.html&#34;&gt;A brief overview of deep learning - Ilya Sutskever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.toronto.edu/~ilya/&#34;&gt;Ilya Sutskever&lt;/a&gt;, also a research director at &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com&#34;&gt;OpenAI&lt;/a&gt; is one of the must read posts for any one diving into deep learning for practical applications. It gives you an insight into why it works, some things you must keep in mind for practical purposes and if you love it, you can just dive into comments section for some cool conversation between &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iro.umontreal.ca/~bengioy/yoshua_en/index.html&#34;&gt;Bengio&lt;/a&gt; and Ilya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-course&#34;&gt;Main Course&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;desserts&#34;&gt;Desserts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;side-dishes&#34;&gt;Side dishes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-extraordinary-link-between-deep-neural-networks-and-the-nature-of-the-universe-henry-lin-harvard-and-max-tegmark-mit-https-www-technologyreview-com-s-602344-the-extraordinary-link-between-deep-neural-networks-and-the-nature-of-the-universe&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/602344/the-extraordinary-link-between-deep-neural-networks-and-the-nature-of-the-universe/&#34;&gt;The extraordinary link between deep neural networks and the nature of the universe - Henry Lin (Harvard) and Max Tegmark (MIT) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why deep learning works?&amp;rdquo; - This is one of the most intriguing questions for all involved in deep learning. We try to convince ourselves giving various answers for the question, similarity with the eye structure, universal approximator, etc. Our friends from MIT and Harvard have come up with a much better, mathematical but still a bit vague explanation for the success of deep learning, by comparing the laws used to predict physical phenomenons and how we can derive complete physics using few rules and parameters, thus explaining the whole world around us. For similar reasons, all visual information can be explained/derived from small parameters. The blog gives a beautiful insight into this relation and for more mathematical treatment one can look into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arxiv.org/abs/1608.08225&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>