<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>deep-learning on Dora's world</title><link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/tags/deep-learning/</link><description>Recent content in deep-learning on Dora's world</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:14:56 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Glimpse of Re-Work Deep Learning Summit - Singapore, 2017</title><link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/glimpses-of-rework-deep-learning-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:14:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/glimpses-of-rework-deep-learning-2017/</guid><description>Last week of April 2017, I was attending Re-work Deep Learning Summit in Singapore. I was representing Qure.ai and speaking about some of the work we have been doing in this field. The conference had speakers from Google Deepmind, Baidu Silicon Valley AI Lab, Facebook; startups such as Kata.ai, SmartCow.ai; investor firms such as Zeroth.ai, etc. In this post, I will introduce to you about all the impressive ideas I learned about in the conference.</description></item><item><title>Tutorials in NIPS 2016</title><link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/nips-2016/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 19:10:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/nips-2016/</guid><description>This is a collection of all material I was able to find for various tutorials of NIPS 2016 for people who were not able to attend it and are really excited to know whats going on and can&amp;rsquo;t wait for official videos and slides.
Crowdsourcing: Beyond Label Generation Link
Variational Inference: Foundations and Modern Methods Slides
Deep Reinforcement Learning Through Policy Optimization Slides
Nuts and Bolts of Building Applications using Deep Learning - Andrew Ng Slides Video from talk by Andrew Ng on same talk but somewhere else is here</description></item><item><title>Deep Learning and AI videos</title><link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/deep-learning-ai-videos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 17:38:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/deep-learning-ai-videos/</guid><description>I like to hear things in my background while I am working. Music seems pleasure but sometimes also a distraction. At such points I play some good random videos in background. These help me in gaining new knowledge but at the same time does not distract me from work. I have compiled a small list of such videos in deep learning that I have heard so far and loved them. Will go on adding more.</description></item><item><title>The End of Deconvolutions</title><link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/the-end-of-deconv/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 17:28:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/the-end-of-deconv/</guid><description>Deconvolutions were introduced in 2014 in &amp;ldquo;Fully Convolutional Networks for Semantic Segmentation&amp;rdquo; and has been extensively used in Semantic Segmentation and Generative Adversarial Networks. But its saturated now and the problems involved with it including checkerboard effects play a huge role in the error it produces. This blog post goes down the journey of deconvolutions and problems associated with it. It also suggests some solutions and how it can be replaced by better alternatives such as subpixel-cnn.</description></item><item><title>Hugo Larochelle TEDx</title><link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/hugo-larochelle-ted/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 18:13:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/hugo-larochelle-ted/</guid><description>This TED talk takes you through the journey of Deep Learning in last ten years and its amazing to see how it has evolved from a time when neural nets were not trusted and there were just a few countable people working, to today when there are so many people that you can find 4 research groups working on a similar idea at the end of the day. Pretty insightful and interesting and in a way it shows how a new technology comes into play and we should keep looking for small kicks, they maybe the thing of the future.</description></item><item><title>Cool NN and DL applications</title><link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/cool-nn-dl-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 14:54:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/cool-nn-dl-applications/</guid><description>Deep learning and Neural Networks have some really cool applications (ideas), and here are a few I have come across and are really tangential to mainstream applications.
Defeating Image Obfuscation with Deep Learning This paper from Cornell and University of Texas at Austin uses DL to reconstruct the images which are pixelated, blurred or encrypted using privacy-preserving photo (P3) algorithm. These techniques are many times used to hide the identities in some sensitive videos and photos in various media.</description></item><item><title>Good deep learning posts</title><link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/good-deep-learning-blog-posts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 18:50:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/good-deep-learning-blog-posts/</guid><description>I am an avid reader and spend a lot of time commuting between home and work. I use this time to read blogs, news and papers. In this article I present some cool blog posts that I found and a very short summary. I will add more links as time permits. I have divided blog posts based on the audience it caters to, beginners and intermediate. I believe experts would dive directly into reading papers and won&amp;rsquo;t spend much time reading blogs.</description></item></channel></rss>