<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experiences on Dora&#39;s world</title>
    <link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/tags/experiences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experiences on Dora&#39;s world</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 13:40:33 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/tags/experiences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories and Learnings from my 1st year in IIT</title>
      <link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/memories-and-learnings-from-first-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 13:40:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/memories-and-learnings-from-first-year/</guid>
      <description>This is a letter, I wrote in my senior year to one of the juniors describing my first year and what I learned from it.
These are my views. I want you to comment and us to discuss, it would enrich both of us. You know most of the things about my freshie year. So I won’t go into things which you already know. Fill it with your memory.
When I came into IIT, I was a completely ignorant child with just one thing in mind that IITians God hote hai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing up - A journey of life</title>
      <link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/growing-up-a-journey-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 15:48:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/growing-up-a-journey-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Last 2 years have been the turning points of my life. I rewind back this time and here I am, a happy-go-lucky guy, laughing all time, playing around and no seriousness at any moment of time. Most of us are like this at this time I suppose. I am 20 now, sitting in Korea, here for an internship with Samsung electronics, and in this period, I have lost things very valuable to me but gained a lot of experience at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From an unknown to someone</title>
      <link>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/from-an-unknown-to-someone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 15:40:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shubhamjain0594.github.io/post/from-an-unknown-to-someone/</guid>
      <description>Yo Junta, this is Shubham Jain a student at IIT Bombay. Being an IITian, I always encounter someone who wants some advice, guidance on how to go for JEE, is he capable and all. So I thought why not just write down my experience and share with world. I know there are already many blogs on this and my blog isn’t any different apart from fact its my personal experience which for me is very different than others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>